<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-09-06T12:11:54+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">AIoT Lab</title><subtitle>Cutting-Edge Research on Artificial Intelligence of Things</subtitle><entry><title type="html">[No.1] Tech Talk Series – “AI in Medical Imaging: Current and future perspectives”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/talk-series-no1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[No.1] Tech Talk Series – “AI in Medical Imaging: Current and future perspectives”" /><published>2022-09-06T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2022-09-06T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/talk-series-no1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/talk-series-no1"><![CDATA[<p><b>Abstract:</b> Medical image analysis is an active research field where advanced image analysis solutions are developed to predict, diagnose or monitor diseases. It is in high demand due to its better precision compared with conventional diagnosis in many scenarios. In particular, many tasks in medical image analysis have achieved human-level performance with the support of advanced machine learning and computer vision techniques. However, the development of effective AI-based solutions for medical image analysis and putting them into everyday clinical use, however, is challenging due to the lack of large, annotated datasets and explainability ability. This talk covers current and future perspectives in medical imaging. I will go through key concepts and applications of medical AI as well as discuss some challenges &amp; potential research directions in the field.
<br />
<br />
<b>
Link đăng ký: <a href="https://bit.ly/3TMWAAI">https://bit.ly/3TMWAAI</a>
<br />
Thời gian: 15h30 chiều thứ 7, ngày 10/09/2022
<br />
Địa điểm: Phòng A6 105, Đại học Phenikaa
<br />
</b></p>

<h3>BIOGRAPHY</h3>
<p><br />
Dr. Pham Huy Hieu is a Teaching Fellow at the College of Engineering and Computer Science (CECS), VinUniversity, and a Research Fellow cum Associate Director at VinUni-Illinois Smart Health Center. He received his Ph.D. in Computer Science from the Toulouse Computer Science Research Institute (IRIT), University of Toulouse, France, in 2019. Previously, he earned the Degree of Engineer in Industrial Informatics from Hanoi University of Science and Technology (HUST), Vietnam, in 2016. His research interests include Computer Vision, Machine Learning, Medical Image Analysis, and their applications in Smart Healthcare. He is the author, co-author of 30 scientific articles appeared in about 20 conferences and journals such as Computer Vision and Image Understanding, Neurocomputing, International Conference on Medical Image Computing and Computer-Assisted Intervention (MICCAI), Medical Imaging with Deep Learning (MIDL), IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP), and IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV). He is also currently serving as Reviewers for MICCAI, ICCV, CVPR, IET Computer Vision Journal (IET-CVI), IEEE Journal of Biomedical and Health Informatics (JBHI), and Nature Scientific Reports.
<br />
Before joining VinUniversity, Dr. Hieu worked at Vingroup Big Data Institute (VinBigData) as a Research Scientist and Head of the Fundamental Research Team. With this position, he led several research projects on Medical AI, including collecting various types of medical data, managing and annotating data, and developing new AI solutions for medical analysis. More details about his research and teaching works are available at <a href="https://huyhieupham.github.io/">https://huyhieupham.github.io/</a>
<br /><br />
<br /></p>
<h3>AIoT Lab:</h3>
<p><br />
•	Web: <a href="https://aiot.phenikaa-uni.edu.vn/">https://aiot.phenikaa-uni.edu.vn/</a> <br />
•	Facebook:  <a href="https://facebook.com/aiot.lab">https://facebook.com/aiot.lab</a> <br /></p>]]></content><author><name>Phạm Huy Hiệu</name></author><category term="Talk series" /><category term="Informative" /><category term="Medical" /><category term="Technology" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[uses layouts to create a static website.]]></summary></entry></feed>